I beleive the American Dream is still alive. In fact, I'll bet a million dollars on it
You, my friends, was labeled a loser least likely to success. No one thought I would ever make
Billionaire Glenn Stearns is betting a million dollars he can take a hundred bucks and grow it into a million dollar business in just 90 days
If it's a penny short of a million, I'll put 1 million dollars into it. But to keep experiment fair, I'm gonna do it all undercover. I won't use my name, my money or my connections. Win or lose in the city of Erie and the people who help me get there will be rewarded, but they don't know it
With a million dollars of his own money on the line, Glenn Stearns will see once and for all if the dream is still possible in America
In his first week in Erie, Pennsylvania, billionaire Glenn Stearns gave him self a goal of making $3.300 to cover his living expenses for the entire 90 days.. but feel short
With just under $415 in his pocket, he's got 82 days left to build a million-dollar business
I fell like crap. I've been sleeping in my truck for over a week and a snowstorm came in last night. I made roof over my head
Need to make money. I need to get going
I can't stop throwing up. Just scared. Don't know what's wrong with you
Do you want to keep going?
- What do you want to do?
- I have to go to the hospital
I made my first million at 28 years old. The reality is I'm not in a 28 years old body anymore. I gave myself a goal of make $3.300 before I get an apartment but if something's seriously wrong with me, I don't know if I'm gonna be able to keep going
- What's the lastest greatest?
- It doesn't look like you can see anything on the x-ray which is nice and you know, my blood pressure's back to normal. My fever is gone. So, I hope I dodged a bullet
Check me out, don't have a flu, so put some fluids in me and actually feeling a lot better. Ryu's dude poisoning or in fact, it basically run down
The last thing I need right now is a hospital bill but I'm happy to pay $250 to know that I'm ok and then I can keep going
I got to get out of strut. You just can't build a business the way I'm living right now. I've gotta get place
I still haven't hit my goal of covering my living expenses for 3 months and I don't have any money to get into an apartment. Not only that, but I'm 9 days in and I still have no idea what business I'm gonna start
I need my million dollars idea but I still need to make some money
I've been checking abandoned lots along the rail line searching for industrial tires and wrought iron to resale. I've got almost every lot out there but there's a few left to try
Fencing, tires, looking a little bit more promising back here
Find your buyer first and work backwards. I know some buyer and willing to pay 4 or $500 for industrial tiers so I'm gonna continue searching along the rail line to meet that demand
Let's well look at this tire first. Here's a good one right? Here. Alright. Look at this, man
There we go. This is comedian lower. I've got these on my ranch. Finding the freakin needles and the haystacks. Can't get any better that this
That's the might be good, too
- Hello
- Hey, is this Cody
- Yes
- I was reading your ad, about you tires and I think I got 4 or 5 of them that you may be interested in
- Ok, perfect
- Hey Cody
- Hey
- How you doing
- I'm not too bad. What do we have here?
- That might be a little tiny tractor or something
- It's like a pickup tire
- Is it
- No, that one there's pretty wore down
- How this one's looking?
This one's really old. Yeah, it's a lot of dry rot on this one. The tread, see all the dry cracks. That's not any good either.
- I think we'll pass on these two. Interesting these ones
- That's some kind of military tire, right?
- Yeah, Deuce and a half. This is for like a large loader or a forklift log loader.
- It's got a lot of life in it still
- What are you looking at to get out of them
- I was thinking about well 1800
- With the cuts and stuff upright, can't go that much price. You like 1400?
- 1400
- So you level with me, how about 69
- I'll do 15
- 15, oh you got a deal with. Hey thanks
- Cash alright?
- Cash works great matter of fact
That's exactly what I needed. Ok, just get beat up, beat up, beat up working here ass off and I've finally hit the big one
I didn't make my goal but I've got enough for a place to live. I need to make do with the money I have and keep moving forward. Finally
- Hi, it's Bob. Is it?
- Yes, it is
- Bob, hi, my name is Glenn Bryant. Listen, I'm looking for a budget-friendly apartment and wanted to know if you had anything available
- What's your price range?
- Well, about $400 a month
- Perfect, I am available anytime. I could come over even right now.
- Sure
- Thank you very much
I am going to find an apartment at least hunting for on today
When I was first researching living expenses, I budgeted $625 a month for an apartment but since I didn't hit my first financial goal, I need to come in much lower than that
I'm hoping I can get into an apartment for $400, you know, I'm not expecting to be in a great place see what I could afford
I'm gonna show you these 2 apartments up here. This is gonna be one of the apartments number 9 here. Got a decent-sized bathroom, nice storage here is wild tub and shower and this is gonna be 405
- Where's the bedroom?
- This would be your bed room. This is considered efficiency. This would be your living room and bedroom combine
- I think you'll like this one here. This is gonna go into your kitchen and what's nice about this. You get French doors great here. Nice little fake fireplace
- What's this one run
- This is gonna be about 435 and it's gonna include just your water sewer trash. I would need a first month's security deposit. You have any question?
- Can I give you my first month's rent and then give you half the deposit and I can two weeks and half the deposit?
- I can't do that. I would need a security deposit up front to hold the unit because if I had another client that came in and put down the security deposit right on the spot. Money talks
- Ok. Alright, I'll take it
So, I ended up with the more expensive apartment. $435 vs $405 but reality, I'm off the road. I don't have anybody in the side of me so there's a lot of things that make this one just a much more efficient apartment and there's something I can live in for the next 90 days
- There's that for you.
- It's hard to belive that I feel so happy to have a place
Perfect. You know when I'm sitting in my car and having to worry abount where I am. It doesn't allow you to think about business or growing anything and just in survival mode. So having you own place, it's such a huge deal
No toilet paper, no bath towels, no so. Even though it's not the Taj Hahal, it's a place just to call my own
I've been so used to living a cush life and now, everyday figuring out how to make 5 or 10 dollars or how to get a job, doing anything finding, you know, some other's person trash on the side of the road, that's worth something
Anyway, it's a very humbling experience. I'm grateful I have a roof over my head right now but I really need a place where I can start a thrive and get my confidence back
Glenn Stearns will see once and for all
With my living arrangements set, I now have to figure out what business I'm gonna start. I'm running out of time but I have a plan and I'm hoping this will save me before it's too late
The truth is starting a successful business is to choose something that the market need and build a great team. Identify a need and fill it. But I also need to do this in less than 3 months
If I'm gonna build a million dollar business, I need to use local resources here, in Erie
- Hi, Glenn
- How are you?
- So nice to meet you
- I've heard a lot of grate things
- Yeah, well, we're exicted to have you. So, you've decided to be an entrepreneur and that's what exactly what we're here to do is help in these new ventures so
Thousands of communities accross the country have a small business development center. These center often have resources for business owner include consulting, office space, computer access and research
The best part of the SBDC is that these services are offered for free
- This is a shared space, we use this classroom, we use this meaning, we use this conference room
- So if I were building my team, I could utilize this space
- Yes
- Ok, great
This is the Beehive. The Beehive is all around business development building business plans, feasibility of business ideas market, research things like that. We can't run your company for you but we make sure you're prepared to do it
I am absolutely exicted. I mean the SPDC is a wonderful resource. I mean it's like everything you could ever want to start a business right there
- Appreciate it off ladies bye-bye
Now I need to figure out what kind of business I'm going to start
I've done my research and got a couple ideas that I'm kicking around in my head. However, I haven't been in Erie. I don't know, you know, what's going on in the area. I don't know what I don't know
So I've set up meetings with a few entrepreneurs to see if they can help me figure out which is the right industry for me. I've warned them that the cameras are gonna be following me
The first is Hannah Kirby who runs a coffe shop and it's doing quite well. You know, there's a 7% growth in coffe sales which makes it really the fastest growing segment in the food industry
- You know, I've just arrived in Erie
- Wellcome
- Thank you
It's kind of looking maybe just start a business and you pop up just about everywhere. So, white coffee, what was that, just a passion
Yeah, something I really enjoyed. You know you look at our downtown district, there's only one coffee shop in town and so, it's like why is there not a local space
- So, I just felt like the environment and the ecosystem was the right timing
- The hell is you your business doing
- The business is paying for itself. We've been here like a year now, so, it's going well
I do think that Glenn is coming into the city and a great time we are very focused on growth. You know, people are really rooting for one another because we are I think we're all rooting for the city
Well, my next stop is Chris truck, he own a metal fabrication company. Erie has deep roots and manufacturing and if you gonna start a business here, it has to be something to consider
I'm a custom fabricator. We do anything that goes on the truck. So, steel, aluminum, stainless, we can build anything mild to wild. This truck, for example, we'll get the box taken off the chassis. I'll come out from under it and everything underneath will be replaced so brand-new
- Tell me how does this work
- Yeah, we take steel and we use a plasma cutter. You ready?
- Let's go
- Well, how cool is that
- It's warm
- That's awesome
- 50 ton break slide it in and hit those tabs. There you go
- They used to make these things to last forever you know?
- Yep, and we picked up the dyes in different places. You can still use the dyes in a brand new machine. More steel, four foot shear, 50 ton break
We can cut Bend, just about anything, you know, that we need to do and as we buy more equipment, we can expand our offerings
It's just like a scissor on the back so to come down a little bit on an angle and slighty
It's got. First 4 years have been extremely difficult but I think we're on the outside of it and hopefully next year, we'll, you know, double the business
- So what's been what do you think's been the hardest?
- I'd say funds are tough. Anyone who talks somebody that owns a business thinks that they're rich but we're really rich for about 10 seconds as one check passes, it goes to pay another bill
- As I continue to build out a team, I'd love to talk to you about more stuff. I appreciate this so much. I really great to meet you
Truth be told, I'm not gonna start a metal fabrication company. The amount of startup capital I would need to buy that heavy-duty equipment, it's just cost prohibitive. But man, Chris is talented. So, no matter what business I start, I know I'm gonna need someone like him in my court
I'll tell you a business that's really taking off here in Erie is the craft beer business. It's been growing about 10 to 15% a year. So I'm meeting with Chris Siri Ani who owns the brewery at Union Station
Love to see that's an industry that's worth getting into
We do about 500 barrels a year, 3 days a week we're back here
Making beer and besides our beer, you know, 12 or 24 beer on tap. We have another forty bottles from PA Brewers. Back here we have 6 seven barrels fermenters and whatever we make in 2 or 4 weeks is on top, it's usually gone in another couple of weeks. So very quick turnover which is a lot of planning down the road. Make sure that the pipelines are filled and the pints are fills at the bar
In theory, I think entrepreneurs, in general especially young entrepreneurs are on the same page and working together and collaborating but the Brewers especially
- What's the advantage of being so collaborative two things
- When all the same issues and problems and a lot of us have the same goal, you know, we're all brewing the same thing water yeast hops and barley right? You know, we're done as much as incubator a local brewery to help them open up as far as somebody that wants to open a business. Erie's the right place in the right time now for craft beer
Craft beer looks very promising. These local Brewers seem to support one another and with their help, I can get my product to market very quickly. But I also see the potential in coffee. It can feel the need of a local community and has the potential to compete nationally. I'm gonna get in touch with the Small Business Development Center and have them start researching coffe and beer
So I can determine what the best business to start
Where I land on coffee and beer, I'm gonna need some serious startup funds to get this business off the ground. The best way that I know to make big money is in real estate, so I want to buy a house to flip it to cover the startup cost for my business
But for now, I need to think on a smaller scale. So my goal for this week is $10.000 for the down payment for the flip house. And the best way to do this is by purchasing assets and then using them to make more money
My idea this time is I want to go to car dealers and I want to see if I can't buy some of their trade-ins
Dealerships take hundreds cars as trade-ins every week. Some get reconditioned to be sold on the lot. But cars that are older and have high mileage get sold to auto auctions for a fraction of what they're worth.
If you can buy these cars from dealers before they send them to auction and turn around and sell them yourself. There's the potential to make a hefty profit
Climb em low, sell em high and hit my goal of $10.000
I'm gonna stop into this dealer. You guys just stay where you are. Car dealers get freaked out when a bunch of cameras show up
- How you doing? My question for you, do you sell any or trade ins?
- No, I'm sorry, we're in receivership right now. We just filed for bankruptcy. I can't actually, legally, sell anything on this lot
He said we're not selling anything. So it must have gone under, too bad.
I see some dealerships up here
- Hey Greg, hey Dad, I'm Glenn. I'm just curious you have any cars that you might be sending off to auction that I could purchase here
- Let me check. I'll be right back
- Yeah, ok
- We just don't feel comfortable selling, you know, like a 3, 4, 5 or $6.000 car
- No big deal
Well, that was a bus. I can't believe they're not interested in selling me a car that they're gonna take the auction. Hopefully, it's not the case of the other dealers
This is gonna be my trashcan. It's pretty good. Oh, darn fork
This is my 3rd night. I really don't have anything. I've gotta spend some of that money on probably a bed and something to sleep, at least something to sleep on and some covers and pan and a few other things, but..
he's wagering he can start a million
It was harder than it was in college but I signed up for it so I should be thankful I am thing, you know, it's raining not my truck
So I mean I have to have something to lay on, need a bed. Maybe I maybe just a sleeping bag's fine but something soft
Should I need to get a pan, I need to get a lamp. Wouldn't mind a lamp. I need to get, you know, just your basic needs, right?
Probably a couple glasses. That's about it, I think
-------------------------------------
I can't wait another day to choose the business that I'm gonna start so I'm headed over to the Small Business Development Center to check out the reaseach I asked them for well
- Exicted to delve in and see what you guys have found
- You have a variety of options here
Time is ticking away in its decision time.
- This is it
Exicted to delve in and see what you guys have found.
Most people don't have experience deciphering complex charts and figures. So having the resource like the SBDC can help potential business owner learn what they need to be successful
You mention the particular industry that you interested in were breweries and coffee. We pulled from a number of resources that we have avaiable, so you have an idea of the competitive landscape as well
- What would you say are the pros and cons of these in this?
- Well, coffee, we want everyday. So when we are looking the desire or need or want in the community, our customers coffee shop, that's a very big problem
- Con is the environment can become convoluted because there are so many
- Why don't we do breweries? The ibisworld report is predicting that it's going to be higher growth over the next 5 years. And you see, you know what? What are people drinking? Craft beer when most of those growth comes from
You know when I found in this industry what, at least was exciting for me, was they're not as opposed to new people coming into their industry. They actually welcome it and they try to help you can start it
Yeah, it's a new industry. So, it makes sense for the players to work together, to grow it. A big con and I guess we need to call it that are the barriers to entry because you do need licenses and it take a while to get that done
- Equipment cost go along that right?
- And the pro is you're in the community that like their beer and they also like their craft beers
On average household spend about $100 more beer away from home than they do on coffee so beer, may be it's more profitable but
After hearing all the research, I'm definitely gonna open a craft beer business. People are spending money on it, the industry is in continual growth and it is potential to scale nationally.
Plus, it's a collaborative field, so my plan is to connect with other local breweries to utilize their instructure which will help me with my savings on equipment cost. I know I can make craft beer a million dollar business
I want to start finding team members so I would appreciate it if I could utilize a computer because I want to put a ad out there for recruiting some more people
Absolutely would love to help you with that
Once you have a direction ahead in, one of the most important things you can do is surround yourself with people who can strengthen your weaknesses. I'm gonna post a ad online saying them looking to build a team my brewing business
I want to target people who are passionate about bringing a new local business here in Erie. I want to hold an open interview, I want to look for an experienced Brewer and then someone who can really help with website design
If I don't have the right team, I've gotta figure this out
Now that I figure out that I want to start a craft brewery, I've got to see what it takes.
is your full-time job you've got to
cover the basics first before you can
build anything bigger so I need to look
around Erie and figure out what it costs
to survive here I'm gonna have to be
very smart about where I spend my money
if I spent it all on shelter then I'm
screwed so I've got to be very efficient
and look at clever ways of being able to
put a roof over my head
a city of ninety seven thousand people
located in the northwestern part of
Pennsylvania here he is in between
Cleveland Buffalo and Pittsburgh
the first time what strikes me is to
seem the power of what used to be right
the remnants of an industrial city that
had so much life it won the All American
City award in 1972 but with the
outsourcing of American manufacturing
it's seen a steady decline in population
as job providers and families scattered
to make do elsewhere
downtown airy as rebuilding Erie will be
a marathon and not a sprint
I didn't want to pull over and figure
out what is it gonna take for me to live
here you know all the surrounding cities
are a lot more expensive than Erie what