Made roof over my head. 2 weeks into his 90-day challenge. How much is this fun? Glenn Stearns has just over $4.000 in his pocket
Erie is the right place in right time now for craft beer.
- And decided on his million dollars idea.
- I am really about the possibility of craft beer
- Here is to the future
But now, he's back to square 1
- Cheers up
- Alright, thank you so much
- Sure
- Bye bye
I'm so screwed. I've got 90-day deadline and I'm finding out I will not be able to get a license in time. So, I've got to figure out something else that archives that goal
The bad news: My idea to start a brewery has gone up in smoke. I need a brewery license to manufacture my own beer but I can't get one in the 90 day time line that I set for myself
Life is like that. Ok. So, you know you got to just continue to get up and do it again and figure it out. Man, if it's not one thing, it's another
Be ready to pivot. Not every deal goes as planned and a good business persion is always prepared to handle the quick turns and failures. That comes with running or starting a business
Base on my research, they're spending about $100 more on beer than they do on coffee. And talking with loca breweries, I still feel that beer is a sound business stagety. So, I need to be creative and find a business where I can sell beer without Brewers license, but I have an idea
When I was out with my team other day.
- So, what do you think's missing in these brew house?
- I think you pair it with good food
I noticed most breweries don't have food. This could be an oppotunity for a pivot
- There's a police call Federal Hill which is really good at barbecue as well
---------------------------------
- What's the lastest greatest?
- It doesn't look like you can see anything on the x-ray which is nice and you know, my blood pressure's back to normal. My fever is gone. So, I hope I dodged a bullet
Check me out, don't have a flu, so put some fluids in me and actually feeling a lot better. Ryu's dude poisoning or in fact, it basically run down
The last thing I need right now is a hospital bill but I'm happy to pay $250 to know that I'm ok and then I can keep going
I got to get out of strut. You just can't build a business the way I'm living right now. I've gotta get place
I still haven't hit my goal of covering my living expenses for 3 months and I don't have any money to get into an apartment. Not only that, but I'm 9 days in and I still have no idea what business I'm gonna start
I need my million dollars idea but I still need to make some money
I've been checking abandoned lots along the rail line searching for industrial tires and wrought iron to resale. I've got almost every lot out there but there's a few left to try
Fencing, tires, looking a little bit more promising back here
Find your buyer first and work backwards. I know some buyer and willing to pay 4 or $500 for industrial tiers so I'm gonna continue searching along the rail line to meet that demand
Let's well look at this tire first. Here's a good one right? Here. Alright. Look at this, man
There we go. This is comedian lower. I've got these on my ranch. Finding the freakin needles and the haystacks. Can't get any better that this
That's the might be good, too
- Hello
- Hey, is this Cody
- Yes
- I was reading your ad, about you tires and I think I got 4 or 5 of them that you may be interested in
- Ok, perfect
- Hey Cody
- Hey
- How you doing
- I'm not too bad. What do we have here?
- That might be a little tiny tractor or something
- It's like a pickup tire
- Is it
- No, that one there's pretty wore down
- How this one's looking?
This one's really old. Yeah, it's a lot of dry rot on this one. The tread, see all the dry cracks. That's not any good either.
- I think we'll pass on these two. Interesting these ones
- That's some kind of military tire, right?
- Yeah, Deuce and a half. This is for like a large loader or a forklift log loader.
- It's got a lot of life in it still
- What are you looking at to get out of them
- I was thinking about well 1800
- With the cuts and stuff upright, can't go that much price. You like 1400?
- 1400
- So you level with me, how about 69
- I'll do 15
- 15, oh you got a deal with. Hey thanks
- Cash alright?
- Cash works great matter of fact
That's exactly what I needed. Ok, just get beat up, beat up, beat up working here ass off and I've finally hit the big one
I didn't make my goal but I've got enough for a place to live. I need to make do with the money I have and keep moving forward. Finally
- Hi, it's Bob. Is it?
- Yes, it is
- Bob, hi, my name is Glenn Bryant. Listen, I'm looking for a budget-friendly apartment and wanted to know if you had anything available
- What's your price range?
- Well, about $400 a month
- Perfect, I am available anytime. I could come over even right now.
- Sure
- Thank you very much
I am going to find an apartment at least hunting for on today
When I was first researching living expenses, I budgeted $625 a month for an apartment but since I didn't hit my first financial goal, I need to come in much lower than that
I'm hoping I can get into an apartment for $400, you know, I'm not expecting to be in a great place see what I could afford
I'm gonna show you these 2 apartments up here. This is gonna be one of the apartments number 9 here. Got a decent-sized bathroom, nice storage here is wild tub and shower and this is gonna be 405
- Where's the bedroom?
- This would be your bed room. This is considered efficiency. This would be your living room and bedroom combine
- I think you'll like this one here. This is gonna go into your kitchen and what's nice about this. You get French doors great here. Nice little fake fireplace
- What's this one run
- This is gonna be about 435 and it's gonna include just your water sewer trash. I would need a first month's security deposit. You have any question?
- Can I give you my first month's rent and then give you half the deposit and I can two weeks and half the deposit?
- I can't do that. I would need a security deposit up front to hold the unit because if I had another client that came in and put down the security deposit right on the spot. Money talks
- Ok. Alright, I'll take it
So, I ended up with the more expensive apartment. $435 vs $405 but reality, I'm off the road. I don't have anybody in the side of me so there's a lot of things that make this one just a much more efficient apartment and there's something I can live in for the next 90 days
- There's that for you.
- It's hard to belive that I feel so happy to have a place
Perfect. You know when I'm sitting in my car and having to worry abount where I am. It doesn't allow you to think about business or growing anything and just in survival mode. So having you own place, it's such a huge deal
No toilet paper, no bath towels, no so. Even though it's not the Taj Hahal, it's a place just to call my own
I've been so used to living a cush life and now, everyday figuring out how to make 5 or 10 dollars or how to get a job, doing anything finding, you know, some other's person trash on the side of the road, that's worth something
Anyway, it's a very humbling experience. I'm grateful I have a roof over my head right now but I really need a place where I can start a thrive and get my confidence back
Glenn Stearns will see once and for all