For the first time in decades, the next generation of Americans may be poorer than their parents.
Seems like it work harder or make less money.
72% of Americans think the American Dream is beyond our reach.
Is the American Dream dead?
This dream is going to decline in decades.
This billionaire is betting it's alive.
You, my friend, was labeled a loser at least likely to success.
No one though I would ever made.
I went from rags to riches but it's wasn't luck.
30 years ago, Glenn Stearns started with nothing and build a billion dollar landing company - one of the largest in the country.
But have the times changed the principles that got me rich and how I'm gonna get rich again.
But talk is cheap. Right? I'm gonna prove it.
Glenn is betting a million dollar of his own money that he can take a hundred bucks and grow it into a million dollar business in just 90 days.
But I understand that I get treated differently because I'm wealthy.
Well, for most people the desk is stacked against them. So, to keep the experiment fair, I'm gonna do it all undercover.
I won't use my name, my money or my connections.
I'll go to the city where I don't know a soul and I'll start from the bottom with only a hundred bucks, a cellphone with no contacts and an old pickup truck.
I'm gonna work with locals to build this company. Because I know I can't do it alone.
You in or out?
Sounds like a beautiful idea. I'm in.
I know it won't gonna be easy.
his own money he can take a hundred
but I've never been afraid of hard-work.
Pump man on my way.
At the end of the 90 day, Gleen's business will be independently evaluated
If it have a penny short of a million, I'll put 1 million dollars into it.
Win or lose, the people help me get there will be rewarded. But they don't know it.
With a million dollars of his own money on the line, Gleen Stearns will see once and for all if the dream still possible in American.
----------------------------------
gonna do it all undercover I won't use
my name my money or my connections I'll